## Nahaliel Bioni Alves da Silva

Engenheiro de Software | Software Engineer | Tech Lead Next | React | Vue | Flutter | React Native | Senior Developer

Linkedin: <a href="www.linkedin.com/in/nahaliel-bioni">www.linkedin.com/in/nahaliel-bioni</a>
E-mail: <a href="mailto:nbioni.developer@gmail.com">nbioni.developer@gmail.com</a>

Github: github.com/Nbioni Website: nbioni.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Throughout my 11-year career, I have been dedicated to understanding the technology market and mastering various stacks such as Flutter, Next.js, React, Angular, C# .NET, and more. This is how I decided to specialize in Flutter to develop multi-platform applications and Next.js with React and Typescript to create websites with the best performance and SEO we have.

Although this journey may seem inconsistent at first glance, each step has been an opportunity for growth and specialization. I believe that if I had only had continuous experience in one place, I would not have acquired the same level of learning that I have today, which has shaped the professional I am today.

I am married and love spending time with family and friends, especially when it involves music. Singing and playing instruments are more than just hobbies, they are my way of expressing myself. That's why I believe that technology, like music, has the power to move, connect, and transform.

My passion is to create interfaces that not only work but also enchant and provide memorable and inspiring experiences. My main soft skills include being attentive, observant, creative, and authentic. I believe that we should all be empathetic and do for others what we would like them to do for us.

#### **PURPOSE**

My goal today is to be part of a dynamic and innovative environment that provides security and stability, where I can continue to learn and evolve alongside talented professionals while offering my creativity and skills to help drive the company and its solutions.

#### **SKILLS**

- Web: Flutter, Next.js, React, .NET, VueJS, Angular, Dart, Typescript, Javascript, C#, HTML, CSS, TailwindCSS, Material UI (MUI), Bootstrap
- Mobile: Flutter, React Native, Dart, Javascript, Typescript
- Backend: .NET, Node, NestJS, C#, Javascript, Typescript, Prisma ORM, Firebase, Cloud Functions
- B.I.: Qlik Sense, Google Analytics

#### **EXPERIENCE**

• Senior Software Engineer - MusicPlayce

Goiânia, Goiás, Brazil - Remote - (August 2024 - now)

- I refactored the MusicPlayce app from version 3 to 4 using Flutter, Firebase, and Flutter Bloc with Cubit, significantly reducing costs and code complexity.
- I implemented AI-powered search using Algolia and deep links with BranchIO, enhancing user experience and engagement.
- I contributed to project documentation on Confluence and provided support to junior developers.
- I defined engineering tasks, guided the development team, and collaborated with the product team on strategic decisions.
- I've implemented a web system for managing the MusicPlayce application, with which it's possible to control Landing Pages and other application features. This web project was developed using Next.js, Tailwind CSS and Firebase.
- Technologies: Flutter, BLoC Cubit, Firebase, Cloud Functions, Nex.js, Tailwind CSS, Algolia, BranchlO, Figma, Confluence.

Keywords: SR, Sênior, Senior, Senior, Software Engineer, Frontend, Front-End, UI/UX, Design, Tech Lead, Flutter, Flutter Modular, MobX, Bloc, Next.js, Next, React, React.js, ReactJS, .NET, ASP, CORE, Vue, Vue.js, VueJS, Angular, C#, Node, NodeJS, Node.js, HTML, HTML5, CSS, HTML/CSS, SCSS, JavaScript Javascript, JS, Dart, TypeScript, TypeScript, TS, Tailwindcss, TailwindcSS, SEO, Search Engine Optimization, Marca, Branding, Material Design, MUI, Qlik Sense, Firebase, Google Analytics, Gestão de Processos, Liderança, Process Management, Leadership.

## · Senior Software Engineer - SST Informática

São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil - Remote - (October 2023 - July 2024)

- I completed a migration from a complex legacy system to new practices and architectures in Next.js and React which resulted in the scalability of the project, generating new contracts for the company.
- I developed an animated website in Next.js and TailwindCSS with a contact form and sent emails.
- I created the basis of a .NET MVC system migration for some modules in Next.js with React and Typescript.
- Technologies: Next.js, React, Typescript, MUI (Material Design), TailwindCSS.

## Senior Software Engineer - Auretto Incorporadora

Maringá, Paraná, Brazil - Remote - (February 2023 - October 2023)

- Mapping and management of the company's processes, from property acquisition to sales.
- Meetings to define culture and strengthen the brand (branding).
- Website development in Next.js with React, Typescript, and TailwindCSS.
- Skills: Leadership, Process Management, SEO, Branding.

### Software Engineer - Codelitt

Miami, Flórida, Estados Unidos - Remote - (May 2022 - February 2023)

- An international company with an international team, I had the opportunity to define and write software
  architecture documentation. I developed the basis of the project in Flutter, taught the architecture, and
  together we developed an Atomic Design System and an extension for Chrome (<u>Property Radar</u>) that
  reads addresses on the current page and queries the API showing the properties that exist in the
  client's system and the entire purchase and sale history of the properties located and the owners'
  contacts.
- Flutter project with clean architecture and state management with MobX.
- I provided maintenance on a web system in VueJS.
- Technologies: Flutter, Dart, Javascript, VueJS, HTML/CSS, Figma.

### • Senior Developer | Tech Lead - Trinus Co.

Goiânia, Goiás, Brazil - Remote - (June 2021 - May 2022)

- I led a team in the development of a backend solution in NestJS with Prisma ORM and the institutional website in Flutter, which strengthened the Trinus brand by emphasizing branding very well.
- I led the development of a portal for the company's brokers and clients to monitor the status of contracted services. This portal generated transparency in the processes, which resulted in a great increase in the level of client confidence, further strengthening the brand.
- I trained the app bank's mobile team (<u>Trinus</u>) in software architecture.
- I developed a POC for a website with 3D interaction with building and apartment models for better customer immersion.
- I implemented Clean Architecture standards and the <u>Flutter Modular</u> architecture created by the <u>Flutterando</u> community.
- Skills: Leadership, People Management, Branding, SEO, Design Pattern, Design Systems.
- Technologies: Flutter, Dart, HTML/CSS, Javascript, Prisma ORM, Figma.

## Software Engineer - K2 Improving Performance

São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil - Remote - (November 2020 - January 2021)

- I developed a Management and Payments system for Banese Bank.
- Skills: Design Patterns, Communication.
- Technologies: .NET, Javascript, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap

#### Senior Developer - TOCTEC

Goiânia, Goiás, Brazil - (February 2020 - May 2020)

 I developed an application called <u>Tocbim</u> in Flutter using BLoC architecture with integration to a BIM (Building Information Modeling) system where the engineer approves or disapproves stages of the work and this already updates the 3D model of the building. This system has brought automation to a process that used to be done manually with paper reports, which has resulted in buildings being built in less time and more contracts for the company.

#### Full-Stack Developer - Lidere Soluções

Goiânia, Goiás, Brazil - (October 2019 - February 2020)

- I developed an application called <u>Conecta WAM</u> for <u>WAM Gestão</u>. This app was developed in React Native and facilitated access to the portal's functions for WAM's clients.
- I provided maintenance on the WAM portal implemented in PHP, making adjustments to the portal's responsiveness and usability.
- Skills: Sketch, Design, Mobile Development, Design Patterns, Communication.
- Technologies: React Native, PHP, Javascript, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, Sketch, Adobe X.D.

### • Full-Stack Developer - Rede Frota

Goiânia, Goiás, Brazil - (June 2019 - September 2019)

- I developed a fuel station financial management system using Angular, TypeScript for the web solution, and C# .NET for the backend.
- I developed a Scaffold for CRUD screens which resulted in greater delivery of system pages and modules.
- Technologies: Angular, Typescript, C#, .NET, HTML/CSS.
- IT Analyst InfinIT Tecnologia

Goiânia, Goiás, Brazil - (October 2018 - June 2019)

- Maintenance of .NET MVC systems.
- Website development in React.
- I've taken part in Business Intelligence (B.I.) training and consultancy with Qlik Sense.
- Intern Tribunal de Contas do Estado de Goiás

Goiânia, Goiás, Brazil - (November 2016 - October 2018)

- I have developed .NET MVC solutions in C# using layered architecture and Oracle PL/SQL databases.
- I worked on the maintenance of legacy systems in VB6.
- Intern Secretaria Cidadã

Goiânia, Goiás, Brazil - (February 2014 - January 2016)

- I maintained a Delphi 7 system.
- I worked with the SQL Server database, controlling the system and sending payments to "Renda Cidadã" and the "Projeto Pão e Leite" (Bread and Milk Project) in the state of Goiás.

# **EDUCAÇÃO**

- **IPOG** Instituto de Pós-Graduação e Graduação Goiânia, Goiás, Brazil (July 2019 June 2021)
  - Executive MBA, Information Technology Management.
- PUC GO Pontifícia Universidade Católica de Goiás

Goiânia, Goiás, Brazil - (August 2013 - June 2018)

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Engineering.